Finding Aid for Ralph A. Sawyer Papers 1918-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ralph A. Sawyer Papers 1918-1978
Sawyer, Ralph A. (Ralph Alanson), 1895-1978.
1 oversize motion picture film
11.3 linear feet
Physicist, University of Michigan professor, dean of the graduate school; correspondence, writings, speeches, organizational files, audio-visual materials.
85820 Aa/2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dean Ralph A. Sawyer and came to the library in several accessions beginning in 1964. Donor no. 4106
The collection is open for research.
Ralph A. Sawyer was a University of Michigan physicist, distinguished for his research in spectroscopy, radiometry, and various forms of spectrographic analysis, and later in atomic energy research. While at the University of Michigan, and in different administrative positions, Sawyer was responsible for the growth of the University's research program in the 1950s and 1960s.
Sawyer was born in 1895 in Atkinson, New Hampshire. After graduating from Dartmouth in 1915, Sawyer enrolled at the University of Chicago, becoming an assistant in physics in 1917. In 1918 he entered the Navy and designed optical instruments for the Bureau of Ordnance. After leaving the Navy in 1919, he received is Ph.D. degree from Chicago and joined the physics department of the University of Michigan. Sawyer rose to the rank of full professor by 1930. During his career he became a specialist in the fields of spectroscopy, radiometry, extreme ultraviolet spectra, series analysis of line spectra, hyperfind structure of spectral lines and quantitative spectrographic analysis.
During World War II, Sawyer was on leave to serve in the United States Naval Reserve. He was first commissioned as a lieutenant commander and placed in charge of experimental laboratories of the Naval Proving Ground in Dahlgren, Virginia. In 1943, he was promoted to commander, assuming charge of the testing and research laboratory.
When released from the Navy in 1945, Sawyer was appointed head of the ordnance division of the naval ordnance test station at Iyokern, California. In April 1946, he became civilian technical director of the Bikini atom bomb tests (known as known as Joint Task Force One) where he supervised and co-ordinated the activities of more than 500 scientists.
Following the tests, also in 1946, Sawyer was chosen dean of the Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate School of the University of Michigan where he served until 1964. He also served the university as director of the Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project established to explore the peaceful uses of atomic energy from 1951-1959. And in 1959, he was appointed to be university vice president for research.
During this period Sawyer also served as chairman of the governing board and acting director of the American Institute of Physics and president of the Optical Society of America, as well as a member of many boards and panels of both civilian and military research groups. After his retirement from the university in 1964, Sawyer continued to work as a consultant. Sawyer died in 1978.
The Sawyer papers have been arranged into seven series: Biographical/personal; Correspondence; Publications; Speeches; Organizational Files; Visual Materials; and Sound Recordings.
Although the Ralph A. Sawyer collection includes materials relating to all phases of his career, beginning with his studies at the University of Chicago in 1918-1919, the strength of the files are for those activities outside of the University of Michigan, notably his work with the U.S. Navy laboratories, Joint Task Force One, the American Institute of Physics, and the Optical Society of America. Files dealing with his University of Michigan activities are less complete as these materials will be found with the records of those units which Sawyer headed.
Subjects:
American Institute of Physics.; Atomic bomb.; Brazil.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; Germany.; Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies.; Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project.; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.); Optical Society of America.; Physicists--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Sawyer, Ralph A. (Ralph Alanson), 1895-1978.; United States. National Bureau of Standards.; United States. Navy.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Physics.; University of Michigan. Engineering Research Institute.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Vice-President for Research.; World War, 1939-1945.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Bikini Atoll (Marshall Islands); Explosions.; Nuclear weapons.; Ordnance testing.; Sawyer, Ralph A. (Ralph Alanson), 1895-1978.; Scientific equipment.; United States. Navy.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Physics.; University of Michigan. Summer Session. Symposium in Theoretical Physics.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Sawyer, Ralph A. (Ralph Alanson), 1895-1978.; Germany (West); Physics.
Contributors:
Astin, Allen Varley, 1904-1984; Abbitt, W. H.; Ackley, Gardner.; Adams, James P. (James Pickwell), 1895-1969.; Barker, Ernest F. (Ernest Franklin), 1886-1970; Beselson, Bernard R., 1912-; Bradbury, Norris Edwin, 1909-; Brode, Robert B. (Robert Bigham), 1900-1986; Brode, Wallace R. (Wallace Reed), 1900-1974; Dennison, David M. (David Mathias), 1900-1976.; Dow, William G. (William Gould), 1895-1999; Fajans, Kasimir, 1887-1975.; Griffin, Clare E. (Clare Elmer), 1892-1979; Haber, William, 1899-1988.; Hansen, Gerhard.; Harrison, George Russell, 1898-1979; Kelly, E. Lowell (Everett Lowell), 1905-1986; Keniston, Hayward, b. 1883.; Knowles, Hugh Shaler, 1904-; Meader, George, 1907-1994; Paschen, F.; Penney, William George, Sir, 1909-; Price, Derek J. de Solla (Derek John de Solla), 1922-1983.; Randall, Harrison M. (Harrison McAllister), b. 1870.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Seitz, Frederick, 1911-; Snow, C. P. (Charles Percy), 1905-1980; Stratton, Thomas F.; Struve, Otto, 1897-1963.; Taylor, William Randolph, 1895-; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980; Varney, Robert Nathan, 1910-; Vivian, Weston Edward, 1924-; White, Albert Easton, 1884-1956.
Genre/Form:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Biographical/personal
  The Biographical/personal series includes transcripts of oral interview given by Sawyer under the auspices of the American Institute of Physics and the Office of Naval History.
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - Oral interview concerning professional career March 16, 1967, September 24, 1970 (Box 1)
    (American Institute of Physics Interview
  - Oral interview largely concerning association with U.S. Navy, the Naval Proving Ground at Dahlgren, Va., etc. May 1967 (Box 1)
    (Office of Naval History Interview)
  - Reminiscence (Box 1)
  - Military service material
    - World War I (Box 1)
    - World War II (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  Correspondence includes files arranged both by name and by date. Correspondents include professional and university colleagues on topics of research and university business.
  - Abbitt, W. H. 1947-1960 (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Jack 1974 (Box 1)
  - Conference on Administration of Research 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Darrow, Karl K. 1961-1966 (Box 1)
  - Dyjack, Art 1971 (Box 1)
  - Fajans, Kasimir 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1937-1941 (Box 1)
  - National Bureau of Standards 1947-1953 (Box 1)
  - National Research Council 1949-1953 (Box 1)
  - Paschen, F. 1926-1936 (Box 1)
  - Phelps, Fred 1968-1976 (Box 1)
  - Sawyer, George 1974 (Box 1)
  - Stratton, Tom 1965 (Box 1)
  - General
    - 1946-1964 [A-Z], 8 folders (Box 1)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 1)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971-1978 (Box 1)
- Publications
  Publications is a small series that includes drafts and reprints of writings. Several folders in this series pertain to his book Experimental Spectroscopy. There is correspondence about the book, reviews, and publicity.
  - Bibliography (Box 1)
  - Book, Experimental Spectroscopy
    - Correspondence 1937-1953, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Book, Experimental Spectroscopy
    - Correspondence 1954-1963 (Box 2)
    - Reviews (Box 2)
    - Publicity (Box 2)
    - Corrections (Box 2)
    - Miscellanea (Box 2)
  - Short articles
    - Brode, W.R., biographical sketch (Box 2)
    - Lyman, Theodore, for Dictionary of Scientific Biography (Box 2)
    - Lyman, Theodore, for Dictionary of American Biography (Box 2)
    - Randall, H.M., for Journal of the Optical Society of America (Box 2)
    - Six articles for British Dictionary of Physics (Box 2)
    - Spectroscopy for Physics Today (Box 2)
    - Miscellanea (Box 2)
  - Chapter from unpublished book on Analytical Spectroscopy (Box 2)
  - Unidentified manuscript (Box 2)
  - Journal articles 1918-1971, 5 folders (Box 2)
- Speeches
  The Speeches series includes addresses given on the occasion of Sawyer receiving an award or honorary degree. There are also general speeches that have been arranged chronologically, 1948-1972.
  - Michigan Tech Honorary Degree 1959 (Box 2)
  - Alpheus Smith Lecture 1962 (Box 2)
  - Ives Medal Address 1963 (Box 2)
  - New York Applied Spectroscopy Medal, Address 1966 (Box 2)
  - Compton Medal Address 1971 (Box 2)
  - Undated, 1936-1959, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - 1960-1972, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Masters' Breakfast Speeches 1953-1964 (Box 3)
  - Programs (Box 3)
- Organizational files
  Organizational Files is the largest series in the collection. The materials in this series have been brought together from the files accumulated by Sawyer in his capacity as member, officer, and participant in diverse professional organizations and programs. The largest subseries within this series are American Institute of Physics, Joint Task Force One (the Bikini tests), University of Michigan activities (Filed under Michigan, University of), the National Academy of Sciences, Sawyer's various activities with the United States Navy (filed under Navy), and the Optical Society of America. In this series under Travel are files pertaining to Sawyer's 1954 trip to Germany for the U.S. State Department.
  - Air Force Research and Development Command
    - 1949-1958 (Box 3)
  - Alaska, University of; Geophysical Institute
    - 1961-1970, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science
    - 1961-1965, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - American Institute of Physics
    - Minutes 1954-1960, 2 volumes (Box 3)
    - Minutes 1961-1971, 8 folders; 1 volume (Box 4)
    - Correspondence and miscellanea 1954-1964, 10 folders (Box 4)
    - Correspondence and miscellanea 1965-1975, 7 folders (Box 5)
    - Budget and Financial statements 1964-1970 (Box 5)
    - Center for History of Physics (Box 5)
    - Constitution (Box 5)
    - Directorship Search Committee 1965-1966 (Box 5)
    - History and Philosophy of Physics, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Information Systems, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Publications, 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Retirement (Box 5)
    - Taxation of non-profit journals (Box 5)
  - Graduate Physics Program Inspection Visits
    - Clark University 1965 (Box 5)
    - Florida, University of 1959 (Box 5)
    - Maine, University of 1966 (Box 5)
    - Tennessee, University of 1967 (Box 5)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute 1965 (Box 5)
    - Virginia, University of 1965 (Box 5)
  - Graduate Schools, Ranking
    - General, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Institute for Defense Analysis
    - General 1961-1964 (Box 5)
  - International Commission for Optics, U.S. National Committee
    - General 1954-1959 (Box 6)
  - International Union of Pure and Applied Physics
    - General 1960 (Box 6)
  - Joint Task Force One
    - Correspondence Undated, December 1945-September 1946, 7 folders (Box 6)
    - Notebook (Box 6)
    - Memoranda Undated, February 1946-October 1946, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Newsletters (Box 6)
    - Miscellanea (Box 6)
  - Los Alamos, Scientific Laboratory
    - General (Box 6)
  - Michigan, University of
    - Department of Engineering Research, Research Projects 1925-1941
      - Correspondence and miscellanea (Box 6)
      - Reports, 4 volumes; 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Data and Findings, 7 folders (Box 6)
    - Physics department 1919-1966
      - General correspondence, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Emeritus Professors (Box 6)
      - Hansen, G. (Box 6)
      - Pitt Conference 1941 (Box 6)
      - Quadrangle (Box 6)
      - Recommendations (Box 6)
      - Research proposals (Box 6)
      - Studies by Sawyer's Students, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies 1945-1971
      - Administration, Appointment (Box 7)
      - Bretsch, Howard, Reports on Doctoral Degrees 1961, 1965 (Box 7)
      - Committee on Courses report 1935 (Box 7)
      - Committees (Box 7)
      - Government and Universities (Box 7)
      - Hyma, Albert (Box 7)
      - Miscellanea (Box 7)
      - Regents' appointment of successor (Box 7)
      - Retirement (Box 7)
      - Sawyer Seminar (Box 7)
      - Senate committee reports 1965-1971 (Box 7)
      - Statistics (Box 7)
      - Stroke, George W. (Box 7)
      - Surveys (Box 7)
      - University Microfilms conflict of interest controversy (Box 7)
    - Office of Research Administration 1958-1972
      - Correspondence and reports undated, 1967-1972, 11 folders (Box 7)
      - Indirect costs on government contracts 1958-1962, 3 folders (Box 7)
      - Indirect costs on government contracts 1963-1972, 3 folders (Box 8)
      - Willow Run Overhead Rate (Box 8)
      - Faculty compensation for sponsored research (Box 8)
      - Auditor's reports (Box 8)
    - Institute of Science and Technology
      - General (Box 8)
    - Phoenix project
      - General (Box 8)
  - NASA Goddard Space Flight Center
    - General 1961-1965 (Box 8)
  - National Academy of Sciences
    - U.S.-Brazil Joint Study Group on Norms Standards, and Testing
      - Correspondence and memoranda Undated, 1964-1969, 7 folders (Box 8)
      - Notes (Box 8)
      - Reports, 3 volumes (Box 8)
    - Technical. Advisory Committees to National Bureau of Standards
      - Correspondence and reports 1955-1967, 8 folders (Box 8)
      - Correspondence and reports 1968-1969, 4 folders (Box 9)
    - National Research Council, Division of Physical Sciences
      - General 1957-1971, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - National Research Council, Commission on Human Resources and Advanced Training
    - General 1948-1954, 1 volume; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - National Science Foundation, General Commission on Science, the Federal Government, and the Academic Institution
    - General 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Navy (U.S.)
    - Director of Naval Laboratories, Advisory Committee (Box 9)
      - Papers 1965-1968, 3 folders (Box 9)
      - Printed materials and reports, 1 volume; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Naval Ordnance Laboratory, Silver Spring, Md. 1950-1963 (Box 9)
    - Naval Ordnance Test Station, China Lake, Calif.
      - Papers 1944-1967, 3 folders (Box 9)
      - Aircraft Fire Control Advisory Panel (Box 9)
    - Naval Proving Ground (Naval Weapons Laboratory), Dahlgren, Va.
      - Oral history interview with Sawyer regarding his work at NPG 1974 (Box 10)
      - Correspondence 1941-1965, 3 folders (Box 10)
      - Advisory Council minutes 1953-1965, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - History. 1918-1945 (Box 10)
      - Rosters and directory (Box 10)
      - Promotion material (Box 10)
      - Memoranda. etc., 3 folders (Box 10)
      - Armor and Projectile Laboratory reports, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Printed material and miscellanea (Box 10)
    - Naval Reserve 1948-1958 (Box 10)
    - Naval War College 1954, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Subsurface Warfare Conference 1948 (Box 10)
    - Naval Technical mission in Europe Notebook and miscellanea (Box 10)
    - Miscellanea (Box 10)
  - New York University Hall of Fame
    - General 1970 (Box 10)
  - Nuclear Power
    - General 1947-1955, 1970-1973, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Optical Society of America
    - Correspondence 1940-1942, 1951-April 1956, 4 folders (Box 10)
    - Correspondence May 1956-1973, 9 folders (Box 11)
    - Awards committee 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Detroit Meeting committee 1966-1967 (Box 11)
    - Ives Medal committee 1964-1966 (Box 11)
    - Lomb Medal committee 1950-1959 (Box 11)
    - Minutes 1953-1958 (Box 11)
    - Reports, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Travel
    - German trip 1954
      - Correspondence (Box 11)
      - Speeches, 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Newsclippings and miscellanea (Box 11)
    - Taiwan trip 1959
      - General (Box 11)
  - Washington colloquium on Science and Society 1966
    - General (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Newsclippings, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Miscellanea (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks (Box 11)
- Visual Materials
  Visual Materials includes photographs and motion picture films. The photographs consist of portraits and group portraits of Sawyer with professional associations, notably the University of Michigan's Summer Symposium in Theoretical Physics. There are also photographs accumulated from the period when he was associated with the Bikini Atoll bomb tests in 1946. The motion pictures are also of the Bikini testing. For research use, a videotape (U-matic format) has been made of the motion pictures.
  - Photographs
    - Apparatus (Box 12)
    - Bikini atom bomb tests 1946 (Box 12)
    - German trip 1954 (Box 12)
    - Groups
      - AIP governing board (Box 12)
      - Michigan State Teachers of Physics 1920 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Navy and Naval Proving Grounds, Dahlgren, Virginia (Box 12)
    - Portraits, etc. (Box 12)
    - Retirement dinner September 11, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Summer Symposium in Theoretical Physics (Box 12)
    - Visit of Dr. H. Kaiser to Ann Arbor 1963 (Box 12)
    - Visit of Major General Beach, Willow Run 1961 (Box 12)
  - Films
    - Bikini atom bomb tests 1946, 1 U-matic use copy of films; 2 motion picture film reels (Box 12)
      (1 oversize film Separately located)
- Sound Recordings
  Sound Recordings is a small series of two reel-to-reel tapes speeches made by Sawyer over German radio in 1954. The speeches are in German. Sawyer had been selected by the U.S. State Department to tour Germany as part of President Eisenhower's program to share atomic energy information with friendly nations.
  - Recordings of speeches made over German radio 1954, 2 reel-to-reel tapes (Box 12)
    (in German)
Selective Index to Correspondence
This index refers to the "General" section of the Correspondence series except when noted otherwise in an index entry. The index was compiled by Bentley Library staff and a researcher.
Abbitt, W. H.
Sept. 19, 1960; May 12, 1958; March 11, 1957; July 1, 1957; Dec. 10, 1956; Jan. 21, 1954; March 10, 1954; Aug. 5, 1950; Nov. 7, 1950; April 26, 1949; Jan. 21, 1948; Feb. 9, 1947; Nov. 24, 1947
Ackley, Gardner, 1915
Dec. 19, 1959 (in the Office of Research Administration files of the University of Michigan)
Adams, James Pickwell, 1895-1969.
Jan. 23, 1946; July 10, 1946; July 12, 1946; June 6, 1951 (in the Michigan University Rackham Appointment file)
Adams, Marchk F.
July 24, 1959
Air Force Cambridge Res. Lab. Office of Aerospace Research
Jan. 5, 1966
Allen, E. C.
Feb. 6, 1960
American Institute of Physics
Jan. 7, 1957; Jan. 16 1957
American Society for Testing Materials
Sept. 9, 1953
Archer, Hugh M.
Sept. 16, 1970
Ardis, Evart W.
Sept. 28, 1959
Astin, Allen Varley, 1904
Sept. 25, 1964; March 24, 1965; Sept. 16, 1966; Sept. 19, 1966; July 25, 1967; Jan. 30, 1968; Feb. 16, 1968; May 7, 1968 (in the National Academy of Sciences - National Research Council correspondence)
Attwood, Stephan
Jun 19, 1964
Bailey, G.W.
Jan. 15, 1959; March 30, 1959; Aug. 5, 1958; Dec. 3, 1958
Baird Associates
Nov. 15, 1943
Baits, Vera
Sept. 28, 1959
Baker, Charlene
(no date)
Ballard, Stanley S.
Aug. 25, 1978; Oct.19, 1970; Jun 23, 1948
Bardcz, A.
Jun 17, 1957
Barker, Dale
Aug. 9, 1964
Barker, Ernest Franklin, 1886-1970.
April 25, 1945; Oct. 30, 1945; Dec. 26, 1945 (in the Michigan University Physics Department correspondence). July 5, 1946 (in the Michigan University Rackham Appointment file)
Barnes, Clifford A.
July 26, 1966
Bausch & Lomb Optical Co.
Oct.12, 1943
Bennett, Ralph D. (U.S. Naval Ord. Lab)
May 26, 1948; July 2, 1948; July 27, 1948
Benson, Albin
July 16, 1964
Berelson, Bernard R, 1912
Jan. 10, 1958; Feb. 5, 1958; Feb. 14, 1958; Jan. 19, 1960; Feb. 18, 1960 (in the Michigan University Rackham Surveys file)
Beutler, Hans
Feb. 3, 1941; April 23, 1941; April 28; Aug. 4, [1940]; Dec. 9; Dec. 7, 1938
Blaisdell, Warren
March 29, 1950
Boland, William A.
May 6, 1951; Jun 18, 1951; Jun 20, 1951; July 18, 1951; Aug. 22, 1951
Bott, William J.
Jun 9, 1964
Bowles, Gordon T.
Dec. 28, 1949
Boydston, R.W.
Jun 1, 1957
Bradbury, Norris Edwin, 1909-
Feb. 4, 1963; May 14, 1964; Feb. 18, 1965 (in the Naval Proving Ground correspondence)
Bradley, Albert
May 31, 1955
Bradley, George
May 4, 1966
Brady, Joe
May 26, 1964; Jun 3, 1964
Brady, Joseph V.
Oct.5, 1959
Bro, Albin C.
April 15-16, 1948; March 25, 1948; Nov. 13, 1947; Dec. 30, 1947
Brode, Robert B, 1900-
Jan. 17, 1949; May 23, 1949; June 3, 1949
March 23, 1954; April 6, 1954; April 13, 1954 (the last 3 in the Naval Ordnance Test Station correspondence)
Brode, Wallace Reed, 1900-1974.
Sep 7, 1960; Feb. 20, 1960; March 27, 1964
Feb. 20, 1960; March 27, 1964; and March 14, 1957 (in the National Academy of Sciences - National Bureau of Standards correspondence)
Feb. 1, 1952; Feb. 8, 1952; Feb. 24, 1955; March 30, 1955; April 19, 1956; Sept. 11 1956; Sept. 27, 1956; Jan. 24, 1957; Jan. 29, 1957; Feb. 5, 1957; May 15, 1957; Dec. 2, 1957 (in the Optical Society of America files)
Bronk, Detlev W.
April 7, 1953
Brooks, Jack
March 6, 1974
Brown, Michael
Aug. 2, 1958
Burke, Arleigh
March 11, 1959; Jun 2, 1959
Burns, Keivin
Jun 14, 1944
Butts, Joseph S.
Jan. 12, 1955
Cadwell, Sidney
Nov. 26, 1959
Calder, Allen B.
May 5, 1969
Carl Zeiss, Inc.
May 22, 1940; Dec. 2, 1940
Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
April 10, 1950; April 18, 1950
Cattell, Jacques
April 27, 1949
Central Bank of the Philippines
Jun 15, 1964
Chalklin, F. C.
Feb. 24, 1948; March 18, 1948
John D. Chase
Sept. 27, 1968
Chung, Mrs. Won-Yang
April 15, 1963
Church, Deborah
Dec. 24, 1968; Jan. 28, 1969
Clark, C. E. Frazer
May 23, 1958
Conf. Board of Assoc. Research Councils
April 7, 1953; April 23, 1953; Oct.31, 1952
Conf. on Administration of Research
Oct.4, 1951
Cook, Albert B.
Jun 30, 1950
Corcos, Joseph M.
Feb. 1, 1967
Cowley, M. Allen & C.
Oct.26, 1970
Cress, Earl H.
Oct.5, 1959
Crow, Allan B.
Feb. 23, 1948
Crowe, Marguerite O'Loghlin
March 4, 1959
Cunningham, S.B.
April 22, 1941; Sept. 25, 1941
Damaso, Connie
Feb. 2, 1961
Darrow, Karl K.
Oct.16, 1966; Jan. 11, 1962; Jan. 15, 1962; Jan. 20, 1962; Dec. 28, 1961
Dartmouth College
March 26, 1969; April 7, 1969
Davis, James M.
Feb. 11, 1969
Dennison, David Mathias, 1900-1976.
July 7, 1946 (in the Michigan University Physics Dept. correspondence)
Dickey, John S.
Jan. 25, 1962
Dorr, Harold M.
Jun 29, 1964
Dorry, Gertrude Nye
Jun 1, 1963; April 1957
RSA Dougherty (Beth Steel)
Nov. 19, 1979
Dow Chemical Company
Oct.14, 1964
Dow, William Gould, 1895-
July 7, 1960 (in the Michigan University Office of Research Administration files)
Drake, J. F.
Jan. 15, 1958
Eastman Kodak Co.
Feb. 14, 1952; May 8, 1951; April 27, 1951; Jan. 17, 1951; Jun 22, 1950; Oct.20, 1943
Eaton, Mildred (Dept. of Commerce)
Sept. 4, 1951
Edds, Joyce
Nov. 17, 1947
Edmonson, J.B.
March 6, 1952
Eisenhower, Edgar N.
April 30, 1964
Engleman, Chris L.
Aug. 31, 1948
Fajans, Kasimir, 1887-1975.
Nov. 8, 1966; Dec. 15, 1966; Nov. 30, 1967
Fischer, O. O.
Jan. 31, 1947
Fisher, Russell A.
Dec. 5, 1955
Fleming, G.
Oct.6, 1952
Folsum, Dick
Oct.6, 1959
Frsterling, Karl
May 20, 1950
Forsythe, W. E.
Aug. 3, 1928
Foust, Judson W.
Sept. 29, 1959
Frank, Henry S.
May 20, 1959
Freund, C. J.
April 4, 1950
Gaertner Scientific Corp.
Nov. 16, 1943; Nov. 24, 1943; May 28, 1940
Gemmell, Lee
Sept. 8, 1948; Sept. 13, 1948
Gilfillan, Edward S.